<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/Altruism.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-05T12:45:22+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/Altruism.xml</id><title type="html">PhinixBlogs</title><subtitle>PhinixBlogs</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The World Needs You</title><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/The-World-Needs-You" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The World Needs You" /><published>2021-03-05T10:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-05T10:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/The-World-Needs-You</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/The-World-Needs-You">&lt;p&gt;My pitch to you is simple. The world needs more people who think and care about others. It needs you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this at a time when COVID-19 has induced a
massive worldwide shift in how we work, commute and live in general. In
times like these, we tend to care for those who can represent
themselves. Beneath the surface, however, the underprivileged face
harder days, everyday. As they struggle to earn their wages everyday,
they cannot help themselves to break the invisible ceiling created by
the World Order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As businesses continue to suffer heavily due to COVID-19, and a lot of
employees have experienced a pay cut or layoff in consequence. Yet,
these people are able to raise their voices, because they still have
access to the Internet, Electronic Devices, Social Media, and Lingua
Francas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine, a stranger appearing at your doors to share about her
hardships and requests financial support. How likely is it that she
might get help? It seems that someone’s chance of getting help from
you has a much lower probability than those who are already part of
your extended network. A stranger with no connection to you will have
to overcome the fog of suspicion to get help from you. Trust, then, is
easier to establish if they are already a part of your social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a part of someone’s network is easy if you have the right social
credentials. It is because of your social credentials, you get access to
different societies and spaces without high efforts. Yet, for the
people, who have little or no social credentials, this is a great
challenge. In every step, systems and cultural spaces try to restrict
their access. They are invisible because they don’t have assets,
identities or strong financial capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is a vicious cycle.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The invisible people do not have social
credentials because they are poor, and they are poor because they have
little or no access to the credentials that might help them live a
better life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consider these facts. Action Against Hunger reports that globally,
more than adequate food is produced to feed the global population, yet
more than 690,000,000 (Six Hundred and Ninety Million) people still go
hungry. If you’re able to read this, I can assume that you are not one
of them. We seem to belong to the segment of the world population, who
enjoys the freedom to do something altruistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can we do, as the privileged citizens, to help the invisible
people around us? Why should we take the responsibility for another
individual when we are already struggling with our own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With full empathy, we all hit the invisible ceiling of society, culture
and financial systems at some point of our lives sometimes. It seems,
making impact is harder and often unnecessary if the person you’re
trying to help is already thriving. On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;there are
plenty of opportunities to make an impact in the lives of those who live
below us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A common instance of a meaningful impact could be to sponsor an
orphan, semi-orphan, or a needy individual in their endeavours to start
a business, or complete their studies&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; By sponsoring a person who
really could use someone’s help, we are giving these people a chance to
help themselves, rather than promoting the dependency mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to seek out individuals who need help by doing social
research. By surveying our extended network, we can find people with
minimal social credentials. Trust issues are common but doing some
homework before deciding to sponsor someone helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do happen to find an individual like this, and you are able to
support them until they take off, you have invested efforts to help them
break through their invisible ceiling. You have not only supported them
with your financial capabilities but also with your advantage of
knowledge, insight, network and emotional support. And &lt;strong&gt;most people
will remember this act of kindness throughout their life.&lt;/strong&gt; And as they
take off through the shattered glasses, they will see you as a role
model and will be inspired to help others the way you did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Start small&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;by yourself&lt;/em&gt; when you are engaging with this kind of
altruism. It is the best way to get the feel of your impact. Ask your
friends and family to help you seek out needy individuals who are really
determined to work on themselves and have the relevant potential. Build
rapport, get to know them, ask them on their plans. When you have
adequate information on their needs, start sponsoring or mentoring them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few words of caution though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is never ideal to use your efforts for any kind of publicity. Acts
like this with the intention to gain monetary or other kinds of
advantage would only expose you to social mockery. &lt;strong&gt;Always remember
that the world will know you by the impact you make.&lt;/strong&gt; There is no need
for marketing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do check if you are solvent enough to support your own family. Know your
limits. You are making impacts by giving certain underprivileged
individuals the chance to make impacts on future generations. Not many
are able to help others if they are not already helping themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started can seem very daunting. Yet when you start down the path
of altruistic initiatives, you will be surprised to find a lot of allies
to support you. Be on the watch and start to get out of your comfort
zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, you will not only help the world (one person at a
time), but also yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have liked the core message of this blog post, please take some
time to share this with someone who might be interested or inspired to
take action. And as always, I sincerely thank you for being with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mmmonowar&quot;&gt;Muhammad Mustafa Monowar&lt;/a&gt;
Exported from &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; on June 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Taylor Brandon on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Muhammad Mustafa Monowar</name></author><category term="Altruism" /><summary type="html">My pitch to you is simple. The world needs more people who think and care about others. It needs you.</summary></entry></feed>