<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/Contemporary.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-05T12:45:22+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/Contemporary.xml</id><title type="html">PhinixBlogs</title><subtitle>PhinixBlogs</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Acting Responsibly in Times of Pandemics</title><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Acting-Responsibly-in-Times-of-Pandemics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acting Responsibly in Times of Pandemics" /><published>2020-03-20T10:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-20T10:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Acting-Responsibly-in-Times-of-Pandemics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Acting-Responsibly-in-Times-of-Pandemics">&lt;p&gt;A short guide to measures in times of COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the source and nature of threat in times of crisis is important for survival. Amidst misinformation and panic in social media, researchers and doctors are relentlessly collecting data to battle COVID-19 / Coronavirus / 2019-nCov. As lay persons, our duty is to do as advised by the experts. This document outlines some of the recommendations provided by the health experts working at the front line. We recommend that you give this a read and do some reading on your own from this source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief--from-are-we-ready-for-the-new-coronavirus&quot;&gt;Brief — From Are we ready for the new coronavirus?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“On 31 December 2019: China (Wuhan) announces 27 cases of pneumonia related to a seafood and live animal market. On 7 January 2020, a new coronavirus is identified as the cause: 2019-nCoV, renamed COVID-19 by the World Health Organization (WHO) and on 11 February 2020 we have since seen its rapid spread.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forecast&quot;&gt;Forecast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risks — From Pay attention to SARS‐CoV‐2 infection in children&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Most patients with SARS‐CoV‐2 infection are middle‐aged and elderly individuals; the majorities of patients who were critically ill and patients who died comprised frail older adults and individuals with underlying diseases.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Because SARS‐CoV‐2 is an emerging virus, there is no specific antiviral treatment for the disease caused by this virus. Currently, the therapy of SARS‐CoV‐2 infection is symptomatic and supportive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to Expect — From ‘No one is allowed to go out’: your stories from the coronavirus outbreak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There might be death tolls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visa process could tighten&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food and commodite price may spike&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travelling may become difficult&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;International travelers may face block on going home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prejudice or discrimination on Asian origins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lab supply could be disrupted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prices for medical device could rise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliveries could be delayed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students could get stranded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;precaution&quot;&gt;Precaution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking precaution is important. Knowing the mode of transmission helps in taking precautions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modes of Transmission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-are-we-ready-for-the-new-coronavirus&quot;&gt;From Are we ready for the new coronavirus?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transmission could happen from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Close Contact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respiratory Droplet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contaminated hands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infected Surfaces such as metal, glass, plastics for more than 9 days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fecal-oral (may be)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asymptomatic carriers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prevention&quot;&gt;Prevention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we know the modes of transmission, we can take preventive measures as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Are we ready for the new coronavirus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All persons with symptoms should maintain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cough Etiquette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hand Hygiene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Principle of Preventive Action Should Be Applied&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual Alert should be posted at strategic locations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructions on cough etiquette and hand hygiene should be explained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strategic locations include isolation in Private room, restricted access&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visitors should take precaution against contact and droplet before entering Confirmed or Suspected Infected area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preventive measure is required&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as soon as case is suspected&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;includes hand hygiene within 5 moments of interaction, before and after removing facemasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumable Facemask should be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Single Use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If shared between patients, should be cleaned and disinfected before reuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consult this resource for using masks the proper way (WHO’s Advice on Using Masks)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;waste-management&quot;&gt;Waste Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaning staff should use protective equipment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consumables which are not cleanable or disinfectable are Class III Biomedical Waste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transmission of this disease can be reduced&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by detecting and isolating carriers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developing drugs and vaccines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;educating public on prevention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reducing the number of contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-are-we-ready-for-the-new-coronavirus-1&quot;&gt;From Are we ready for the new coronavirus?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The disease may have flu-like symptoms (high temperature, myalgia, respiratory symptoms, and possible progression to pneumonia), although with less abrupt onset, and upper respiratory symptoms appear to be insignificant or absent in coronavirus infection. In both influenza and coronavirus, most patients do not present severe disease, but others may develop pneumonia. In hospitalized patients with COVID-19 pneumonia, 26% required intensive care; 61% of these developed acute respiratory distress syndrome and 30% shock”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;management&quot;&gt;Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Are we ready for the new coronavirus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Management involves isolation, symptomatic treatment, and support measures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Coronavirus disease (COVID-19): The need to maintain regular physical activity while taking precautions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Exercise at home using various safe, simple, and easily implementable exercises is well suited to avoid the airborne coronavirus and maintain fitness levels. Such forms of exercise may include, but are not limited to, strengthening exercises, activities for balance and control, stretching exercises, or a combination of these. Examples of home exercises include walking in the house and to the store as necessary, lifting and carrying groceries, alternating leg lunges, stair climbing, stand-to-sit and sit-to-stand using a chair and from the floor, chair squats, and sit-ups and pushups.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mitigation&quot;&gt;Mitigation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community Mitigation — From Covid-19 and community mitigation strategies in a pandemic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No specific drugs or vaccines are available, and health systems are overburdened everywhere. We have to rely on targeted, non-coercive, community interventions with sufficient transparency and public engagement and trust, and implement them urgently. Such measures may help delay the exponential spread of the outbreak until drugs become available. Transparency and trust are critical to preserving a calm and compliant response to mitigation advice among the public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key community mitigation strategies include-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cancellation of ad hoc events and suspension of events with superspreader potential&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of social distancing measures to reduce direct and close contact between people in the community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel restrictions, including reduced flights and public transport and route restrictions without compromising essential services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voluntary home quarantine of members of household contacts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes to funeral services to minimise crowd size and exposure to body fluids of the diseased&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear communication from national and international health authorities to ensure verified information and avoid fake news, rumours, and panic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel is the single most important contributor to disease transmission. Absolute travel bans may increase fear and affect the travel of essential staff and the timely movement of supplies. Home deliveries of essential commodities may be feasible in some communities. Reduced frequency of transport (flights, trains) and route restrictions could be proposed, along with community sensitisation, aiming to reduce the demand for travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;front-line&quot;&gt;Front-Line&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) From — COVID-19 pneumonia: infection control protocol inside computed tomography suites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PPE includes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eye protection (goggles),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a filtering facepiece respirator (N95),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a surgical cap,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gloves,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a fluid-resistant gown,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and shoe covers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-doctors&quot;&gt;For Doctors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Are we ready for the new coronavirus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Healthcare professionals should wear a gown (if not waterproof and splashes are anticipated, add a plastic apron), FFP3 mask — single use in accordance with European standard EN149:2001 (American equivalent, NIOSH N95), with special emphasis on correct use — gloves and eye protection.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-governments&quot;&gt;For Governments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some learnings from the Governments across the world fighting the Pandemics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Communication, collaboration and cooperation can stop the 2019 coronavirus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In the face of global infectious-disease emergencies, countries have a responsibility to be transparent in their reporting and actions, both to their own populations and to the international community, in order to facilitate and accelerate cooperation that will ultimately curtail outbreaks and minimize harm.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-covid-19-in-singapore--current-experience&quot;&gt;From COVID-19 in Singapore — Current Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its experience with the SARS outbreak in 2003 when 238 people were infected, Singapore has been systematically strengthening its ability to manage another emerging infectious disease outbreak. These include-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the construction of National Centre for Infectious Diseases and National Public Health Laboratory;
    significant expansion in the number of negative-pressure isolation beds throughout the public hospital system;
    stockpiling of personal protective equipment (PPE) and masks;
    establishment of formal platforms for multi-Ministry and cross-agency coordination;
    development of a strong capability to perform contact tracing quickly and at scale;
    training of health professionals including in the correct use of PPE;
    and building more biosafety level 3 laboratories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, as part of Singapore’s major investments in biomedical science and clinical research and translation capabilities, a significant focus has been placed on building expertise in infectious diseases.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-celebrity--popular--religious-figures--from-covid-19-and-community-mitigation-strategies-in-a-pandemic&quot;&gt;For Celebrity / Popular / Religious Figures — From Covid-19 and community mitigation strategies in a pandemic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Mass gatherings and events such as music festivals, religious gatherings, cultural celebrations, conferences, and political events should be restricted. Respiratory infections are most commonly transmitted at such events. Even when the R0 is low, the crowd density during mass gatherings predisposes to high rates of transmission. On 27 February 2020 Saudi Arabia suspended the year round Umrah pilgrimage, and the transmission of covid-19 in the country has been low. This contrasts with Iran, which did not intervene in the religious pilgrimage in Qom and has seen large regional outbreaks. Organisers of other mass gatherings — including the 2020 Olympic Games, Dubai Expo 2020, and Hajj pilgrimage — will need to make decisions about risks and benefits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-businesses--from-covid-19-and-community-mitigation-strategies-in-a-pandemic&quot;&gt;For Businesses — From Covid-19 and community mitigation strategies in a pandemic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Office space is another enabling environment for respiratory disease transmission. New shift work and rotation schedules seeking to decrease social density can minimise disease propagation. Telemedicine, video conferencing, telecommuting, and expanded leave policies may help staff adhere to social distancing policies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst misinformation, what matters is sharing the valuable information. This post was created from research articles written by researchers working at the frontline. Please share the post if you’ve found this helpful or insightful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mmmonowar&quot;&gt;Muhammad Mustafa Monowar&lt;/a&gt;
Exported from &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; on June 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Adam Nieścioruk on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Muhammad Mustafa Monowar</name></author><category term="Contemporary" /><summary type="html">A short guide to measures in times of COVID-19</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some thoughts on Dual-Use Neurotechnology</title><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Some-thoughts-on-Dual-Use-Neurotechnology" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some thoughts on Dual-Use Neurotechnology" /><published>2020-02-08T10:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T10:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Some-thoughts-on-Dual-Use-Neurotechnology</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Some-thoughts-on-Dual-Use-Neurotechnology">&lt;p&gt;Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) is a growing field of study in
Neuroscience. It also intersects with many Neuroethical issues. An
emerging Nueroethical dilemma arising with the application of BCIs is
its dual uses. I recently came across a paper by Ienca et al. (2018).
This post will attempt to provide a brief synopsis and commentary on the
topic of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the Dual-Use Neurotech?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Ienca et al. (2018) the dual-use problem refers to the use
of bio-tech for both civilian and military purposes as well as the
beneficial applications and harmful misuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Neurotech is a sub-branch of Biotech, this definition of dual-use
also applies to Neurotechnology such as BCIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Leuthardt et al. (2004, p.6) a BCI converts brain signals
of the user into outputs which communicates the user’s intents without
using muscles or peripheral nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ienca et al. (2018, p. 269) maintains that non-invasive consumer grade
BCIs are presently available with the use cases of device-control,
self-neuromonitoring and personalized entertainment. Same technology is
used in warfighting equipment modulation for better usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of BCI being used in military funded projects is the DARPA’s
BRAIN Initiative. Clinicians on the other hand have been using BCI to
treat neurological disorders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is, as Ienca et al. (2018, p. 270) puts, an ethical dilemma because
it manifests itself as a conflict between two ethical duties- the
prevention of bad such as military arsenalisation and the promotion of
good such as clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Argument&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The academics argue that Dual-Use Neurotechnology can run in
circularity. That is clinical and consumer-grade application of
neurotech can also seep into military application and vice-versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some scholars have called for a Global ban on Dual-use Neurotechnology.
However, it has to be kept in mind that many of the clinically
beneficial to civilian projects are also military funded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why this is Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors have urged the need for increased monitoring of the dual-use
of neurotechnology. The authors also argue that Neurodevices have the
capacity to alter neural correlates of mental processes. Since, Dual-use
Neurotech are not properly identified in the Human Rights to Autonomy,
Privacy and Mental or Physical Integrity, their harmful uses could go on
unrecognized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors recommend that these uses of dual-use neurotech should be
identified in relation to Human Rights to Autonomy, Privacy, Mental or
Physical Integrity. They also urge that developing codes of ethical
conduct will maximise benefits of military neuroscience and the harms of
civilian use cases. In particular -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clinical Trials should be preceded by safety and effectiveness&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treatment resistant conditions should be prioritised&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unintended collateral damage to brain functions should be reduced&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;IRB approval and informed consent should be followed&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors mention that neuroscientists sometimes may not consider how
their work contributes to warfare. I think this is a very important
point and therefore agree with the authors that establishing a
neurosecurity framework could raise awareness among neuroscientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it can be added as a comment that to monitor dual-use neurotech,
it should be regulated more strictly. For example, DIY BCI could lead to
dual use dilemas of terrorist/rogue state research, however low the
probability might be. On the other hand, it may be riskier to assume
that only military funded projects are destructive. Cases of Corporate
Enterprises such as Facebook has shown that the data of the masses are
not always safe in the hands of corporate entities. Consumer-grade
Neurotech are therefore probably better off being regulated. If the
Neurotech are restricted to Clinical Research only, it might be easier
to monitor and regulate its dual uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Ienca, M., Jotterand, F. and Elger, B.S., 2018. From healthcare to
warfare and reverse: How should we regulate dual-use
neurotechnology?. Neuron, 97(2), pp.269–274.]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Leuthardt, E.C., Schalk, G., Wolpaw, J.R., Ojemann, J.G. and Moran,
D.W., 2004. A brain–computer interface using electrocorticographic
signals in humans. Journal of neural engineering, 1(2),
p.63.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mmmonowar&quot;&gt;Muhammad Mustafa Monowar&lt;/a&gt;
Exported from &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; on June 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Fakurian Design on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Muhammad Mustafa Monowar</name></author><category term="Contemporary" /><summary type="html">Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) is a growing field of study in Neuroscience. It also intersects with many Neuroethical issues. An emerging Nueroethical dilemma arising with the application of BCIs is its dual uses. I recently came across a paper by Ienca et al. (2018). This post will attempt to provide a brief synopsis and commentary on the topic of the paper.</summary></entry></feed>