<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/productivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-05T12:45:22+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/productivity.xml</id><title type="html">PhinixBlogs</title><subtitle>PhinixBlogs</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Some thoughts on prioritizing between tools and work</title><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Some-thoughts-on-prioritizing-between-tools-and-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some thoughts on prioritizing between tools and work" /><published>2021-05-07T10:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T10:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Some%20thoughts%20on%20prioritizing%20between%20tools%20and%20work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Some-thoughts-on-prioritizing-between-tools-and-work">&lt;p&gt;The internet is literally crawling with tools that we can use to increase productivity. Does it imply that we should attempt to make the best use of ‘All’ of these tools as much as we can?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my experience so far. I started out with &lt;strong&gt;Notion&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;strong&gt;Github&lt;/strong&gt;, then various other tools for &lt;em&gt;Academic Writing&lt;/em&gt;. My realizations so far have been these -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I tend to be tool oriented in my work. Which means that I work because I like working with tools, not because I have to work. The upside is that I work as long as I feel like the tool is doing me favor. The downside is also the same. Many seem to call this, ‘Shiny Object Syndrome’&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learning one tool after another takes time. It pays off in the long run. It saves money and it can cost you money. I have tried cheaper methods of productivity and still ended up using expensive productivity software. Learning each tool took a lot of time, from &lt;strong&gt;Emacs&lt;/strong&gt; to GUI based apps to countless mobile apps. It takes time. If I did not have plenty of time to spare, I’d stick to one tool that I felt comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Of course it is hard to keep calm and carry on, but work is important. Work is what matters. No one, at the end of the day, will want to see how productive I’ve been unless there is a result.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Should we try to use as many tools as possible? It depends on the capacity to learn, really. Some people are comfortable with one tool, others need a whole ecosystem of tools. My approach was to learn one tool at a time, judge its pros and cons, and then either keep it in the toolbox or forget about using it again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When there’s a lot of work to do, should we try to be productive or get to work first? The best bet here is to start working, and get productive as we go. When I think of being productive, I mean learning tools for getting work done more efficiently. Unless I start my work, I might not know what my needs are, therefore my suggestion would be to start with work first and then try to pin the specific needs that could be automated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find I am most productive when I balance between work and learning tools well. The trick is to keep a healthy balance between learning tools for automating the repetitive workflows, and using the mind for more complex tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Authored by Muhammad Mustafa Monowar 
Photo by Owen Michael Grech on Unsplash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name>Muhammad Mustafa Monowar</name></author><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">The internet is literally crawling with tools that we can use to increase productivity. Does it imply that we should attempt to make the best use of ‘All’ of these tools as much as we can?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Are Letting Social Media Destroy Your Life. Dont.</title><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/You-Are-Letting-Social-Media-Destroy-Your-Life-Dont" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Are Letting Social Media Destroy Your Life. Dont." /><published>2021-03-18T10:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-18T10:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/You-Are-Letting-Social-Media-Destroy-Your-Life-Dont</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/You-Are-Letting-Social-Media-Destroy-Your-Life-Dont">&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sites you visit are designed to extract information from you. They
give you a false sense of socialization with minimally controlled
incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you like that red notification pop up? Do you like the beep of
messages arriving? Do you like scrolling to the infinite bottom of the
feed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a reason you like to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the most layperson among us notices that algorithmic suggestions
show us the things that we like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are we, then, in denial of its effects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we are addicted to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless they try really hard, addicts cannot help themselves to give up
their addiction. It takes a strong will to give up habits that are
harmful. This post is not about which social media you should quit,
rather a general guideline to help you be aware of what you have gotten
yourself into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;knowing-the-signs-of-good-habits-and-badhabits&quot;&gt;Knowing the Signs of Good Habits and Bad Habits&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding what is good and what is bad can be quite hard in contemporary
times. For the sake of understanding let us define &lt;strong&gt;Good Habits&lt;/strong&gt; as
&lt;em&gt;patterns of behavior that are hard to acquire&lt;/em&gt;, which don’t come to us
naturally, and takes conscious effort to build yet easy to give up.
These habits require our willingness to understand their significance
and effect in our lives. &lt;strong&gt;Bad Habits&lt;/strong&gt;, on the other hand, are the
opposite; we pick up these habits almost unconsciously, and become
addicted to them.These are the behaviors that are very hard to give up.
The only thing common between bad habits and good habits is that they
both have long-term consequences in our lives and those around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that, if you are willing to take measures to reduce
your screen-time and improve the quality of your inner life, help is
here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;some-helpful-techniques-to-overcome-social-media-addiction&quot;&gt;Some Helpful Techniques to Overcome Social Media Addiction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a concept out there that our habits are activated by the way we
interact with our environment. A person who eats a lot, usually has
foods around them that are easily reachable. In our case, we are
activated by the very device that we use ubiquitously. For most of us
who frequently check in to social media sites, Social Media habits are
usually the same .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We keep our social media apps installed. The notifications are always
on for messaging services. We often visit social media sites, hoping
to find something that we cannot describe to ourselves. We pick up our
phone when we are bored, or don’t want to be where we are. If you do
it too, then you, my friend, should do something about it as soon as
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s consider the opportunity cost of these habits. You let
yourself get distracted when notifications hit the bell. You feel
interested to see what’s the fuss about. You feel compelled, almost
automatically, to tap your way into the social media site. Once you get
there, you realize that you can’t help scrolling a bit, and then a bit
more, and on and on it goes on. The people in your life, wait for you to
respond, your children look at you, but you’re absorbed in the device in
your palm, and the people who invited you to talk waits for you to
respond, and ends up behaving the same as you do. In parties, social
gatherings, we don’t socialize anymore, we all go sit together and
scroll on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, with a little awareness, you can change your habits slightly
to battle this addiction. Here’s what I did, and how it has helped me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deleting-social-media-apps-from-cell-phone&quot;&gt;Deleting Social Media Apps from Cell-Phone&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it is safe to announce that I don’t have social media apps
installed in my phone. By deleting these apps from my phone, I am making
it harder for myself to tap and jump into the social media . That is, I
have intentionally made the activation potentials lesser than before,
and this successfully alters my behavior of accessing social media. I do
end up re-installing the apps sometimes. But each time I delete those
apps, I am also forcing myself to refrain from reinstalling the apps in
my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;turn-off-notifications-for-the-messaging-apps&quot;&gt;Turn Off Notifications for the Messaging Apps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a game-changer. I still have some essential messaging apps
installed. The reason for this is mostly because work and networking
culture is gaining momentum in my circles. However, I think most of us
has had these experiences of notifications popping in the middle of
something and effectively interrupting our attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have all my notifications turned off. By doing this, I still get to
see my messages when I am free, but I have more control over my own time
by reducing the possibility to be disturbed by frequent untimely
notifications. Having notifications turned off pays off very well when I
go to sleep, or when I am with my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;recognize-that-social-media-and-your-device-is-basically-a-marketing-technique&quot;&gt;Recognize that Social Media (and Your Device) is Basically a Marketing Technique&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media sites are designed in such a way, that they can make you
behave in a predefined scenario (exactly the way designers would want
you to behave). Most users who are frequently available on social media
follow a common user experience flow that invites them to share
information about themselves, even when it’s not necessary. A
notification, or a shining app-icon that stands out, or even you,
unconsciously reaching out to the keyboard, is the kind of behavior that
the social media engineers would want you to do. Once you respond to
these leads, you are invited to scroll, until you are compelled to pick
up a call to action: a comment, a share, a like, a decision to
subscribe. These sites even give you subtle incentives when you interact
with them. What all these mean is that the design is effective when you
engage with it constantly. By performing the call to action, you
essentially let yourself fall into the trap of lead generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;make-use-of-the-screen-time-monitoring&quot;&gt;Make Use of the Screen Time Monitoring&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned this from my partner, who regularly monitors her screen time.
If your device has a screen time monitoring feature, do make use of it.
Seeing how much we waste time and effort on irrelevant pursuits, can
motivate us to change our habits. With some devices, you can limit the
amount of time you spend on social media. Features like these remind you
when you spend too much time in the wonderland, and effectively
interrupting the continuous flow of doom scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;keep-the-phoneaway&quot;&gt;Keep the Phone Away&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can, put your cell phone away when you don’t really need it. If
you keep a fidget spinner in your hand, you will surely be tempted to
play with it. Similarly, having a device that allows for swiping or
tapping, invites you to engage with the lead generating traps. By
putting your phone away, you let the process of accessing social media
be a bit less easy for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;last-but-not-the-least-smile-and-focus-on-what-needs-to-bedone&quot;&gt;Last but not the Least: Smile and Focus on What Needs to be Done&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media hardly gives you information that you need. Sometimes it
does let you see what you want, but it is only a sign that the social
media knows too much about you, that such insights are being sold to
countless vendors who hacks your mind and convinces you to buy their
products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default we all know that family matters more than social media,
friends matter more than random strangers, and meaningful socialization
matters more than pointless pursuit of interactions. Wisdom has it that
the past cannot be changed, the future cannot always be predicted, but
the present is where we can put effort to change things that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So don’t let irrelevant information distract your purpose, your time
with family and yourself. Value the people who are there with you, in
your life. Time is precious, and so is your attention. Share it with
those who matter, not to things that do not give you anything more
than perpetual anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mmmonowar&quot;&gt;Muhammad Mustafa Monowar&lt;/a&gt;
Exported from &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; on June 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Sydney Sims on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Muhammad Mustafa Monowar</name></author><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">Seriously. Don’t.</summary></entry></feed>