<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/Team.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-05T12:45:22+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/feed/by_tag/Team.xml</id><title type="html">PhinixBlogs</title><subtitle>PhinixBlogs</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Gaining Better Organization Scalability through a Class-based and Team-First Approach</title><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Organization-Scalability-Class-based-Team-First-Approach" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Gaining Better Organization Scalability through a Class-based and Team-First Approach" /><published>2021-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Organization-Scalability-Class-based-Team-First-Approach</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/Organization-Scalability-Class-based-Team-First-Approach">&lt;p&gt;The term Scalability is often mentioned when business owners are planning for rapid expansions in terms of the input and output capacity of their system or the business itself. In the technology domain, this could mean expanding the system capacity to serve more users by increasing the processing power or the number of processing units. The concept of Scalability has also been applied to Organizations in terms of how organizations can expand their operations to serve more customers with increased or more skilled Human Resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For organizations, it is often more profitable to use less input for providing more output. For example, it seems if 5 administrative staff can take care of the administrative processes of 200 employees, it can be attempted to scale in two ways. The owner can assume there is an increase in the quality of skills of the administrative staff over time, and now 5 administrative staff can take care of 400 employees. Alternatively, the business owner may assume, there are fundamental limits to the ratio of administrative staff to regular employees. In such a case, an expansion from 200 employees to 400 employees may require expanding the number of administrative staff from 5 to 10. One is about the quality of input and the other is about the quantity of input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Scalability is a complex phenomenon, precisely because Human beings are dynamic agents and can not be easily modeled by highly simple mathematical formulas. The larger the organization grows, the more complex its internal wiring becomes. Sometimes, this is good, as it serves for an internal dynamics equilibrium. But organizations are complex adaptive systems, and they do not operate discretely from larger adaptive systems within the society. Therefore, when external forces require shifts in way of work within the organization dynamics, larger and more established organizations may find it harder to manage major paradigm shifts than smaller and newer organizations. 
This seems, at the core, a design problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand scalable infrastructure and organization, we may find the atom analogy useful. Atoms are said to be one of the building blocks of our physical reality. In the periodic table, atoms that are larger, are usually more unstable, and tend to break into smaller atoms. Smaller atoms on the other hand are relatively more stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the simplicity of understanding, we can assume that if a team is an atom of an organization, the larger the team, the more chances for it to be unstable. This poses a curious dilemma. If scaling is attempted on the quality side of input, it increases pressure on the team. If scaling is attempted on the quantity side of input, it increases chances of unstable dynamics. In both cases, the team performance is affected, which in turns could impact the organization itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are we to address this dilemma without getting biased on treating humans as inert objects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, my hypothesis is to design teams by limiting team members at a minimum size. Doing this might offer support in terms of team stability. The more stable a team is, we can assume, the more chances of the team to be tight-knit in their bonding and therefore ability to produce quality work through teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if the goal is to ensure the stability of atomic units of the organization, so that the organization scales well, how do we do this and what could be the implications given the optimization (or optimization failures)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion in this case is to keep a team size limited to 4-5 members. Furthermore, instead of having fixed division of task roles, where each team member works on siloed domains, a better alternative is to recruit team members based on classes. For example: in administration, a team of four could be given four distinct fixed work domains. No one interferes with another’s business, and over time siloed behavior emerges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tackle the silo within teams, the concept of classes may be useful. It assumes that some people are good at executing technical tasks, while others are good at people handling. Some people may be very good at presenting the final work while others have a deeper understanding of how things actually work. I was inspired by a blog-post by Harold Jarche to conceive four fundamental classes for teams-design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scholar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Executive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Representative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of classes assumes that scholars are usually good at the domain of knowledge management, leaders are good at the domain of people management, executives are good at project management and representatives are good at customer relationship management. Note that the classes themselves do not define what tasks the team members will do, but rather predict the pattern of distribution of the tasks that a self-organizing team might make when dealing with assignments. The concept of classes also assumes that classes exhibit the strength and interests of a person that also overlaps with a team (organization) function. The specialization of a class is compensated by other class specialization. At the same time, when getting things done, it can be assumed that one class has less complete dominance over the rest. Because each of these classes work in a different domain of specialization, each team-members can then assume a temporary lead based on the need of the task or work and class specialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One possible shortcoming of this hypothesis is rooted in the over-optimism that team cohesion works well based on specialization. The team-members may be very well specialized in their own domains but still not go along well. How to ensure this requires an entire different domain of research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, assuming that the team functions better with this limited number of members, we can also further argue that inter-team siloes could also emerge. I have given this some thought, and to me, it seems siloed behavior cannot be obliterated fully. But it seems that for scaling through increasing team-numbers (and not team member numbers), it could work better than having large departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there is the need for the team to report to someone more experienced and with more responsibilities so that information about activities are compressed when they reach the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this, I believe Inter-Team and Intra-Class (ITIC) groups are helpful. For example, three teams work on three different projects. The leader-class-assuming-members of these three teams can belong to an ITIC group, led by a more senior leader class representative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their book, “Team Topologies” Manuel Pais and Matthew Skelton argue that strictly hierarchical models (based on org-charts) are less effective than team-first approach. The class based approach seems aligned with their framework, both of the theories argue for preserving the atomicity of teams as important for scaling to larger organizations. A lot of unexpected situations can emerge when trying to put this theory forward in practice. For example, how do we make use of a situation when there is a shortage of representatives in one class and an overabundance of another? What happens when team members do not go along well despite their specialization? These questions need further thought. This is still in the early stage of a work in progress, and the suggestions generated are to be perfected through overcoming obstacles in practice. The class-based approach, for now, seems a good starting point for team design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Written by Muhammad Mustafa Monowar
Photo by Brooke Cagle on Unsplash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name>Muhammad Mustafa Monowar</name></author><category term="Team" /><summary type="html">The term Scalability is often mentioned when business owners are planning for rapid expansions in terms of the input and output capacity of their system or the business itself. In the technology domain, this could mean expanding the system capacity to serve more users by increasing the processing power or the number of processing units. The concept of Scalability has also been applied to Organizations in terms of how organizations can expand their operations to serve more customers with increased or more skilled Human Resources. For organizations, it is often more profitable to use less input for providing more output. For example, it seems if 5 administrative staff can take care of the administrative processes of 200 employees, it can be attempted to scale in two ways. The owner can assume there is an increase in the quality of skills of the administrative staff over time, and now 5 administrative staff can take care of 400 employees. Alternatively, the business owner may assume, there are fundamental limits to the ratio of administrative staff to regular employees. In such a case, an expansion from 200 employees to 400 employees may require expanding the number of administrative staff from 5 to 10. One is about the quality of input and the other is about the quantity of input. Unfortunately, Scalability is a complex phenomenon, precisely because Human beings are dynamic agents and can not be easily modeled by highly simple mathematical formulas. The larger the organization grows, the more complex its internal wiring becomes. Sometimes, this is good, as it serves for an internal dynamics equilibrium. But organizations are complex adaptive systems, and they do not operate discretely from larger adaptive systems within the society. Therefore, when external forces require shifts in way of work within the organization dynamics, larger and more established organizations may find it harder to manage major paradigm shifts than smaller and newer organizations. This seems, at the core, a design problem. To understand scalable infrastructure and organization, we may find the atom analogy useful. Atoms are said to be one of the building blocks of our physical reality. In the periodic table, atoms that are larger, are usually more unstable, and tend to break into smaller atoms. Smaller atoms on the other hand are relatively more stable. For the simplicity of understanding, we can assume that if a team is an atom of an organization, the larger the team, the more chances for it to be unstable. This poses a curious dilemma. If scaling is attempted on the quality side of input, it increases pressure on the team. If scaling is attempted on the quantity side of input, it increases chances of unstable dynamics. In both cases, the team performance is affected, which in turns could impact the organization itself. How are we to address this dilemma without getting biased on treating humans as inert objects? Here, my hypothesis is to design teams by limiting team members at a minimum size. Doing this might offer support in terms of team stability. The more stable a team is, we can assume, the more chances of the team to be tight-knit in their bonding and therefore ability to produce quality work through teamwork. So if the goal is to ensure the stability of atomic units of the organization, so that the organization scales well, how do we do this and what could be the implications given the optimization (or optimization failures)? My suggestion in this case is to keep a team size limited to 4-5 members. Furthermore, instead of having fixed division of task roles, where each team member works on siloed domains, a better alternative is to recruit team members based on classes. For example: in administration, a team of four could be given four distinct fixed work domains. No one interferes with another’s business, and over time siloed behavior emerges. To tackle the silo within teams, the concept of classes may be useful. It assumes that some people are good at executing technical tasks, while others are good at people handling. Some people may be very good at presenting the final work while others have a deeper understanding of how things actually work. I was inspired by a blog-post by Harold Jarche to conceive four fundamental classes for teams-design. Scholar Leader Executive Representative The concept of classes assumes that scholars are usually good at the domain of knowledge management, leaders are good at the domain of people management, executives are good at project management and representatives are good at customer relationship management. Note that the classes themselves do not define what tasks the team members will do, but rather predict the pattern of distribution of the tasks that a self-organizing team might make when dealing with assignments. The concept of classes also assumes that classes exhibit the strength and interests of a person that also overlaps with a team (organization) function. The specialization of a class is compensated by other class specialization. At the same time, when getting things done, it can be assumed that one class has less complete dominance over the rest. Because each of these classes work in a different domain of specialization, each team-members can then assume a temporary lead based on the need of the task or work and class specialization. One possible shortcoming of this hypothesis is rooted in the over-optimism that team cohesion works well based on specialization. The team-members may be very well specialized in their own domains but still not go along well. How to ensure this requires an entire different domain of research. Also, assuming that the team functions better with this limited number of members, we can also further argue that inter-team siloes could also emerge. I have given this some thought, and to me, it seems siloed behavior cannot be obliterated fully. But it seems that for scaling through increasing team-numbers (and not team member numbers), it could work better than having large departments. Then there is the need for the team to report to someone more experienced and with more responsibilities so that information about activities are compressed when they reach the top. For this, I believe Inter-Team and Intra-Class (ITIC) groups are helpful. For example, three teams work on three different projects. The leader-class-assuming-members of these three teams can belong to an ITIC group, led by a more senior leader class representative. In their book, “Team Topologies” Manuel Pais and Matthew Skelton argue that strictly hierarchical models (based on org-charts) are less effective than team-first approach. The class based approach seems aligned with their framework, both of the theories argue for preserving the atomicity of teams as important for scaling to larger organizations. A lot of unexpected situations can emerge when trying to put this theory forward in practice. For example, how do we make use of a situation when there is a shortage of representatives in one class and an overabundance of another? What happens when team members do not go along well despite their specialization? These questions need further thought. This is still in the early stage of a work in progress, and the suggestions generated are to be perfected through overcoming obstacles in practice. The class-based approach, for now, seems a good starting point for team design. Written by Muhammad Mustafa Monowar Photo by Brooke Cagle on Unsplash</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The A-Team</title><link href="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/The-A-Team" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The A-Team" /><published>2020-07-30T05:19:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-30T05:19:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/The%20A-Team</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phinixgreen.github.io//phinixblogs/The-A-Team">&lt;p&gt;If you were a designer, equipped with a special design-machine that allowed you to add people with different traits and skills to create teams, what kind of Team would you like to build?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ideal go-to would be an A-Team, which is often defined as a group of people who can survive almost anything. Sounds cool, but is it possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An A-Team in the corporate world is not about just getting things done in Bond-like manner. No, that would be awful. In fact, the A-Team I imagine is much more capable. It is not something you just get with hiring people (or design with a special design-machine). It’s far from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’re some of my hypotheses for building an A-Team -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t start with work. It would be pretty awful to start right away with business without getting to know who your team-mates are. Give them space and time to get acquainted with each other. It is more important than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Realize that you are not a manager. You are a leader. There’s a difference between the two. A manager makes people work, even though they don’t want to do it. A leader works together with the team, guides them, gives them feedback and often at times learns from them. If you think you’re the one in-charge, forget about building an A-Team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Know your team well. People are a curious kind, with amazing feats and strange potentials to be found. If you don’t know your team, you don’t know what they know, and they don’t know what you know. Knowing with human curiosity is one of the hardest things to do these days. It is easy to ask people formal questions, but knowing their needs and preferences is rare.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t start serious-work before you have adequately known your team. An arrow needs to be pulled back before it can shoot far with great velocity. Give your team that time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Come to a common agreement, some ground rules within the team that everyone agrees with. 
Forget about performance appraisal systems. I think most experts would agree that performance appraisal systems are broken. Learn to give feedback. Teach often and learn often.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even though your team doesn’t believe in performance management, your organization might. The team may want to prove that it is capable. Keep count of every task, and priorities. Discuss before diving into the work. Ask questions, take responsibility of projects. Know your capacity and deliver in time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At times, your team will come across challenging tasks. In those moment, there will be conflicts, there will be frictions. Whatever happens, one thing cannot be let go. That is the Team-Spirit. The team must believe in itself. One failure is everyone’s failure, and one success if the whole team’s success.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even still, the strongest will fall. May be a loved one will pass away, may be someone will fall sick, or will be in need of help. Always keep your team together and be there. An A-Team is not about just work, it’s about sticking together through rainy days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On most occasion, your team will certainly fail. They might face humiliation and experience conflicts. Don’t let it break the team. Let the team fall back and resolve the hidden conflicts. Understand the burnout. Heal the wounds and get back on track.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Occasionally, your team will accomplish truly great feats. Remember these moments. Always make these moments memorable.&lt;br /&gt;
A-Teams are agile, yet they are human. Alone they may fall but together they stand tall. A-Teams are about nurture and growth. It’s about sharing responsibilities and burdens. It’s about knowing, paying attention, being there and co-creating.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With time, the A-Team will grow fierce, not because they will have new powers or tools, but they have consistently and persistently held onto each other. It will be beautiful journey, one that will be worth remembering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to grab this opportunity to thank the HR-Team of BCPCL for their amazing contribution and feats in the past few months. We are a group of young HR professionals who are relentlessly working to add value to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;First published on July 30, 2020 in LinkedIn 
Photo by fauxels from Pexels 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Muhammad Mustafa Monowar</name></author><category term="Team" /><summary type="html">If you were a designer, equipped with a special design-machine that allowed you to add people with different traits and skills to create teams, what kind of Team would you like to build?</summary></entry></feed>